Guide to the Cornell University Class of 1937 (Women) records, 1937-1997.
Cornell University Class of 1937 (Women) records, 1937-1997.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Class of 1937 (Women) records, 1937-1997.
41-4-738
Cornell University. Class of 1937 Women.
6.5 cubic ft.,
Correspondence, programs, pamphlets, photographs, memoranda, memorabilia, questionnaires, clippings, audiotapes, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the Class of 1937 Women's Secretary, Carol Cline, include correspondence, programs, pamphlets, photographs, memoranda, and memorabilia pertaining to reunions; questionnaires and other biographical information for each reunion; a guide for class secretaries, clippings, and other printed material; "Class of 1937 Women, History Since Graduation, 1937-1990," and tape recordings of the Women's Reunion Banquet and Midnight Dormitory Party (1962), Introduction to 1937 Banquet, and the 45th Reunion Banquet at the Johnson Art Museum. Also, questionnaires about the class, 1972-1991.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of the Class of 1937 Women's Secretary, Carol Cline, include correspondence, programs, pamphlets, photographs, memoranda, and memorabilia pertaining to reunions; questionnaires and other biographical information for each reunion; a guide for class secretaries, clippings, and other printed material; "Class of 1937 Women, History Since Graduation, 1937-1990," and tape recordings of the Women's Reunion Banquet and Midnight Dormitory Party (1962), Introduction to 1937 Banquet, and the 45th Reunion Banquet at the Johnson Art Museum. Also, questionnaires about the class, 1972-1991. Class of 1937 class and reunion records; and reunion memorabilia, particularly "Flip the Frog" class mascot items.
Also contains files of Merle Ohlinger, including correspondence with Carol Cline. Reunion photographs (1947, 1957, 1962) and parody issue "Naval Day Nudes, May 23 1936."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Class of 1937 Women.; Cline, Carol Helen, 1915-1985.; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.
Subjects:
Class reunions.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Women of '37 correspondence, 1938, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Women of '37 correspondence, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- '37 correspondence, 1942-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Women of '37 correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Women of '37 correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Women of '37 correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Women of '37 correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
- Women of '37 correspondence, 1966-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Women of '37 correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Women of '37 correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Mrs. Helena Abendschein, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Re: Mrs. Abendschein, Chaperone, Sigma Delta Tau; incl. photo of Mrs. A., correspondence with Mary Donlon, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Mrs. N. Carter Daniel, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Letters to Dilly (Esther Dillenbeck Pruden), re: 25th anniversary gift for Carol Cline, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Dean R. Louise Fitch, 1941-1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Prof. John C. Adams, Shakespeare prof., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Helen E. Fry '37, mainly re: her service with the American Red Cross in North Africa and Italy, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Margaret W. Thompson, Assistant to the Dean of Women, 1935-1940; 1944-1948 letters, with the American Red Cross in China, 1940-1951 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Miscellaneous correspondence since 1962, incl. letter from Edith M. Fox, Oct. 21, 1963, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Class of 1937 records, A-G, 1937-1943 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Class of 1937 records, H-N, 1937-1943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Class of 1937 records, O-S, 1937-1943 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Class of 1937 records, T-Z, 1937-1943 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- 1937 women, 10th Reunion questionnaires #1, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- 1937 women, 10th Reunion questionnaires #2, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- 1937 women (correspondence, newsletters) #3, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- 1937 women biographical records, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Class of 1937, 15th Reunion questionnaires #1, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Class of 1937, 15th Reunion questionnaires #2, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Class of 1937, 15th Reunion correspondence #3, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 15th Reunion (newsletters from Cline), 1937, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 20th Reunion questionnaires #1, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 20th Reunion questionnaires #2, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 20th Reunion correspondence #3, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 25th Reunion Ringbook #1, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 25th Reunion Ringbook #2, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 25th Reunion Ringbook #3, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Mostly Reunion 1962, 1955-1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Mostly Reunion 1962, 1948-1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 1937 Women 25th Reunion, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 25th Reunion reservations, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- '37 Reunion, 1962, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- '37, 30th Reunion, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- '37 Newsletter (carbons), 1947-1957 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
- Alumni Fund, 1937-1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Copies for Alumni News, 1938-1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Copies for Alumni News, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence with 1937 Women's Officers about Alumni News, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Class Secretaries Association Meeting, 1940-1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- A Guide-book for Class Secretaries, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Cornell Alumni News, 1937, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Cornell Club of Dayton, 1939-1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Cornell Dramatic Club, 1951-1960 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Federation of Women's Clubs, 1943-1962 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- '37 Reunion photos, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- '37 Reunion photos: 30th, 35th, 40th, 45th, 1967, 1972, 1977, 1979, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Hinchliff: Letter from Cornell, 1947-1960 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Non-official Reunion Years - literature, 1948-1961 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Reunion material and miscellaneous, 1954-1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Reunion workshop materials, 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- 1955 Reunion - miscellany (Box 3, Folder 23)
- 10th Reunion - miscellany, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Cornell University class reunions, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- 1972 Reunion miscellany (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Sigma Delta Tau, 1941, 1947, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- '37 Directories, 1958, 1972, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Women of 1937 Directories, 1942-1962 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- '37 Directories, 1958-1965 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Newsclippings, 1948-1959 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Cornell buildings (Box 3, Folder 32)
- 1939 Reunion and Class News (also '36), 1949-1964 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Newsletters concerning 1939 Women's 40th Reunion, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Cornell '37 Mortar Board Round Robin, 1937-1943 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Cornell '37 Mortar Board Round Robin, 1944-1949 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Cornell '37 Mortar Board Round Robin, 1950-1984 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Class of '37 Newsletters, 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Class of '37 Newsletters, 1948-1961 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Class of '37 Newsletters, 1962-1972 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Class of 1937 scrapbook, 2nd and 5th reunions, 1938-1942 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- '37 women pictures, 1939, 1947, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Class of 1893 letter to class secretaries, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- LIFE, June 7, 1937 (features class of '37) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Album of Cornell songs made for Cornell Alumni Assoc. (6 sides) (Box 5)
- Recording of Cornell songs (2 sides) (Box 5)
- Class of '37 banner (Box 5)
- Freshman beanie (Box 5)
- White blazer and skirt, '37 emblem (Box 5)
- '39 button and ribbon, Elizabeth D. Stocking (Box 5)
- Book, You Can Take Them With You, by Violet Brown Weingarten '35 (Box 5)
- 5 reunion buttons (Box 5)
- Printing block, cut for banquet program, 15th reunion, 1952 (Box 5)
- Shoe cleaner, compliments of Ithaca Hotel (Box 5)
- Origami frog, 10th reunion, 1947 (Box 5)
- Reunion photographs, 1947, 1957, 1962 (Box 5)
- "Naval Day Nudes" parody issue, 1936 (Box 5)
- Postcard from Merle Ohlinger to Miss Marian Stevenson, n.d. (Box 5)
- "Flip" - stuffed frog, Class of '37 mascot (Box 6)
- Cowbow hat with button from 1952 reunion (Box 7)
- Crew hat (Box 7)
- Metal reunion mugs, (6) (Box 7)
- Buttons (4) (Box 7)
- Small Cornell banner (Box 7)
- "How to care for your wild rock" (Box 7)
- Megaphone (Box 7)
- Reunion beer bottle (Box 7)
- Baseball cap with button "Cincinnati next" (Box 7)
- V. U. centennial goblet in box (Box 7)
- Cornell banner (Box 7)
- Carol Cline letters, 1940s (Box 8)
- 30th Reunion questionnaires and class correspondence (Box 9)
- 40th Reunion questionnaires and photographs (Box 9)
- 45th Reunion questionnaires and photographs (Box 9)
- Directories, class correspondence (Box 9)
- Reunion booklets, senior banquet menu (Box 9)
- Reunion files (Box 10)
- Class letters (Box 10)
- Photograph (Box 10)
- Class history files (Box 11)
- Files (Box 12)
- Reunion programs (Box 13)
- Files (Box 13)
- Paper miscellany (Box 13)
- Files (Box 14)
- Printing block (Box 15)
- Frog stickers (1 roll) (Box 15)
- Ceramic frogs (2 green, 1 white) (Box 15)
- Frog (1-$1 bill origami) (Box 15)
- Reunion buttons (2) (Box 15)
- Reunion files (Box 16)
- Carol Cline letters (Box 16)
- "Flip" the frog (new crocheted version) (Box 17)